1995年 一个名叫安迪的男孩在生日时得到了一个巴斯光年玩具
In 1995, a boy named Andy got a Buzz Lightyear toy for his birthday.
这是他最喜欢的电影中的内容
It was from his favorite movie.
这就是那部电影
This is that movie.
未知的空间 距离地球420万光年
UNCHARTED SPACE 4.2 MILLION LIGHT YEARS FROM EARTH
星际指挥部SC-01探索船 船员：1200人
STAR COMMAND SC-01 EXPLORATION VESSEL CREW: 1200
巴斯光年任务日志 星际日期3901
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date 3901.
传感器检测到潜在的生命形式
Sensors have detected potential life forms.
在一个未知的星球上
on an uncharted planet.
因此 我们要绕道调查
So, we're making a detour to investigate.
太空巡警将进行初步评估
Space Rangers will make initial evaluation,
然后评估是否值得把科学人员从超级睡眠中唤醒
then assess whether it's worth waking the science crew
是否值得把科学人员从他们的超级睡眠中唤醒
from their hyper-sleep.
当ERIC号采集核心样本时
While the ERIC takes core samples
我将进一步探索这个陌生星球的怪异之处
I will explore further the oddities of this strange planet.
地形似乎有点不稳定
Terrain seems a bit unstable.
还没有读出该地区是否可以呼吸
No read-out yet if the area is breathable.
似乎没有任何地方有智慧生命的迹象
There seems to be no sign of intelligent life anywhere.
-你在和谁说话？-没有人
-Who are you talking to? -No one.
你又在叙述了
You were narrating again.
我没有 只是在做任务记录
I was not. Just doing the mission log.
你知道没有人听他们说过
You do know no one ever listens to them.
我知道 叙述有助于我集中注意力
I know that, narrating helps me with focus.
-保持敏锐 -是的
-Stay sharp. -Yeah.
好吧 如果它困扰着你 霍桑指挥官
Well, if it bothers you, Commander Hawthorne.
我很高兴等萝卜回来
I'm happy to wait back on the turnip.
请不要叫它萝卜
Please don't call it the turnip.
但这艘船看起来像根蔬菜
But the ship looks like a root vegetable.
是的 你在设计审查时说得很清楚
Yes, you made that very clear at the design review.
你知道我解说有多久了？
How long have you known that I narrate?
永远 自从你和我还是学员的时候
Forever. Since you and I were cadets.
说到这里 你忘了带着那个菜鸟
Speaking of, you forgot to take the rookie with you.
啊 霍桑指挥官 你知道我对新秀的感觉
Ah, Commander Hawthorne, you know how I feel about rookies.
这和我对自动驾驶的感觉一样
It's the same way I feel about autopilots.
"有什么可以协助你的吗？有什么我可以做的吗 先生？"
"How may I assist you? Is there anything I can do, sir?"
他们没有帮助 他们只是把事情搞得过于复杂
They don't help, they just over-complicate things.
我最好还是自己来做这件事
I'm better off just doing the job myself.
这就是为什么我带来了这个新秀
Which is why I brought the rookie.
你好
Hello.
-不 -巴兹 协议要求我们把他带上
-No. -Buzz, protocol requires we bring him along.
-他将会有一双悲伤的眼睛 -巴兹
-He's gonna have sad eyes. -Buzz.
你知道我不能处理悲伤的眼睛
You know I can't deal with sad eyes.
-看看这个新秀 巴兹 -不
-Look at the rookie, Buzz. -No.
-看那只罗... ...看... -不... ...不
-Look at the roo...Look... -No...no.
-光年 -不
-Lightyear. -No.
-看他 -不看
-Look at him. -Not looking.
-看 -看 -不
-Look. Look. -No.
-看看这个新秀 -不 不
-Look at the rookie. -No. No.
好的 好吧 好吧 你赢了
All right. All right. You win.
看 费瑟... 费瑟汉姆斯坦...
Look, Feather...Featheringhamstan...
是Featheringhamstan 长官
It's Featheringhamstan, sir.
听着 菜鸟 首先 除非有人说话 否则你不能说话
Look, rookie, first, you will not speak unless spoken to.
-是的 长官 -仍在说话
-Yes, sir. -Still talking.
第二 尊重这套衣服
Second, respect the suit.
这套衣服意味着什么
This suit means something.
它不仅仅是在保护你的身体 更是在保护整个宇宙
It's not just protecting your body, it's protecting the universe.
这套衣服是对世界的一个承诺 你
This suit is a promise to the world that you,
只有你会做一件事 而不是其他
and you alone will do one thing above all.
不惜一切代价完成任务
Finnish the mission no matter the cost.
你永远不会放弃 不管银河系会给你带来什么... ...
You will never quit, whatever the galaxy may throw your way--
请你把它关掉！
Will you please turn that off!
这也太容易了
It's just too easy.
你在嘲笑我 是吗？
You're mocking me, aren't you?
是的 但是以一种支持的方式
Yeah, but in a supportive way.
听着 我想说的是 指挥官 你和我已经把这项工作搞定了
Look, what I'm trying to say, Commander, is that you and I have this job down.
-长官 -还在说
-Sir. -Still talking.
在任何时候我都知道你在想什么 我知道你会去哪里
At any moment I know what you're thinking, I know where you're gonna be.
但这个人 我不知道
But this guy, I don't know.
他去哪了？
Where'd he go?
你看到了吗？这正是我所要说的
You see? This is exactly what I'm talking about.
他不是在帮忙 他走神了
He's not helping. He's wandered off.
籐条！
Vines!
虫子！
Bugs!
这艘船 它正在下沉
The ship. It's sinking.
各位 回到萝卜上！
Everyone, back to the turnip!
哦 所以现在是萝卜了
Oh, so now it's the turnip.
启动隐身模式 这应该为我们争取到足够的时间
Engage Stealth Mode. That should buy us enough time.
我们不会成功的
We're not gonna make it.
快到了！
Almost there!
好了 B计划 准备好了吗？
Okay, plan B. Ready?
开始！
Go!
-爆炸！-在这里 我可以重新安排路线
-Blast! -Here, I can re-route it.
给我点时间
Just give me a minute.
哪里是...
Where is the...
救命啊！
Help!
菜鸟
rookie.
救救我！
Help me!
巴斯光年任务记录 这个星球显然是不适合居住的
Buzz Lightyear mission log. The planet is clearly uninhabitable.
事实上 完全是敌对的
In fact, outright hostile.
有知觉的叶子已经逮捕了学员弗斯-费瑟林...
The sentient foliage have apprehended cadet Furth-Feathering...
费瑟林斯顿...费瑟...费瑟...
Featheringston...Feather...
他们抓到了这个新秀
They got the rookie,
我强烈建议他一开始就不应该加入...
who I strongly suggested should not have joined in the first--
爆炸
Blast.
-嗡嗡声！-现在！
-Buzz! -Now!
快走吧 游侠！
Move it, ranger!
我们正在返回船上的路上
Making our way back to the ship.
来吧 巴兹！
Come on, Buzz!
快点！
Hurry!
引擎室一切正常
All good at the engine room.
-我来掌舵 -而且我将--
-I'll take the helm. -And I will--
什么都不做 我有了这个
Do nothing. I've got this.
有什么需要我协助的吗？
How may I assist you?
自动导航仪
Autopilots.
-有什么我可以做的吗 先生？-没有 也没有！
-Is there anything I can do, sir? -No and no!
这不是一个模拟
This is not a simulation.
指挥官 状态！
Commander, status!
燃油投入
Fuel engaged.
所有系统运行
All systems go.
警告 发射弹道不健全
Warning. Launch trajectory unsound.
快来吧 来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
碰撞迫在眉睫
Collision imminent.
弃权 终止
Abort. Abort.
光年船长 你需要我的帮助吗？
Captain Lightyear, do you need my help?
-不需要 -你确定吗？
-Negative. -Are you sure?
我是巴斯光年 我总是很确定
I'm Buzz Lightyear. I'm always sure.
我是巴斯光年 我一直都很确定
s.ub by su.b .T
情况很糟 巴斯
It's bad, Buzz.
超速水晶被完全摧毁了
The hyper-speed crystal was totally destroyed.
长话短说：我们被放逐了
Long story short: we're marooned.
我不知道
I don't know.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我在把自己送上军事法庭
I'm court-martialing myself.
不 你不可以
No. You're not.
霍桑指挥官 我特此解除自己所有太空游侠的职责
Commander Hawthorne, I hereby relieve myself of all Space Ranger duties.
这是我的错 而这些人应该得到更好的待遇
This was my fault. And these people deserve better.
你可以把我关进牢房
You can throw me in the brig.
完成任务 巴兹
Finish the mission, Buzz.
这就是我们所做的
That's what we do.
我们要等到所有人都回家了才算完成任务
We're not done until everyone gets home.
但我们没有燃料晶体
But we have no fuel crystal.
所以我们在这个星球上开采资源 创造一个新的晶体
So we mine resources on this planet, create a new crystal.
水晶核聚变是非常不稳定的
Crystalic fusion is highly unstable.
然后我们测试它
Then we test it.
不 这太危险了
No. It's too dangerous.
制造一种能够超速运转的晶体
Manufacturing a crystal capable of hyper-speed
就像试图用太阳套索一样
is like trying to lasso with the sun.
然后需要有人把太阳连接到飞船上
And then someone would need to attach that sun to a ship,
然后这艘船需要有人来驾驶它而不把自己炸成碎片
and then the ship needs someone to fly it without blowing themselves into oblivion.
谁在他们的头脑中会...
Who in their right mind would...
巴斯光年任务日志 星际日期3902
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date 3902.
在被放逐了一整年之后
After a full year of being marooned,
我们的专业人员
our specialized crew
已经把这个星球的大量资源用到了不可思议的地方
have put this planet's vast resources to incredible use.
终于 我们的第一次超速试飞开始了
Finally, our first hyper-speed test flight is a go.
准备好了吗 光年船长？
Ready, Captain Lightyear?
我已经准备好了 霍桑指挥官
Ready as I'll ever be, Commander Hawthorne.
准备好了
To infinity.
还有更远
And beyond.
-嗡！-我们在外围有一个缺口
-Buzz! -We got a breach in the perimeter.
来吧 我只是...
Come on, I just...
光年队长！
Captain Lightyear!
飞行员迪亚兹
Airman Diaz.
孩子们 今天的籐蔓有点凶猛 是吧？
Boy, the vines are a little feisty today, huh?
我们准备好发射了吗?
Are we ready to launch?
如果你准备好了 我们都准备好了 先生
We're all ready if you are, sir.
一年的努力换来四分钟的飞行 这不是很了不起吗？
A year of work for a four minute flight. Isn't that something?
当然是
Sure is.
好吧 让我们去看看这个新的超速燃料是否稳定
Well, let's go find out if this new hyper-speed fuel is stable.
这样我就可以让我们离开这块石头了
So I can get us off this rock.
我差点忘了 这是你的I. V. A. N 先生
I almost forgot. Here's your I.V.A.N, sir.
满载
Fully loaded.
自动导航仪
Autopilots.
当然 这里是XL -01
And here, of course, is the XL-01.
相当不错的旅程
Pretty sweet ride.
现在让我们给你的燃料晶体
Now let's get you that fuel crystal.
早上好 光年船长
Good morning, Captain Lightyear.
这是你特别配制的混合燃料
Here is your specially formulated fuel mixture.
那么 这就是能达到超速的燃料？
So, this is the fuel that's gonna reach hyper-speed?
它有87.6%的机会
It has an 87.6 percent chance.
我愿意接受这个概率
I'll take those odds.
祝你好运 船长
Good luck, Captain.
我们都指望着你...
We're all counting on you...
飞行员
Airman.
XL -01呼叫任务控制中心 你收到吗？
XL-01 to Mission Control. Do you copy?
收到 XL -01
Copy, XL-01.
我准许你在四分钟内离开地球
I'm gonna grant you four minutes to be off planet,
但你要马上回来找我们
but then you come right back to us.
这是个命令
That's an order.
收到
Roger that.
超速 我来了
Hyper Speed, here I come.
T减10...
T minus 10...
...9...
...nine...
...8 7...
...eight, seven...
...六...
...six...
...五 四...
...five, four...
...三、二...
...three, two...
...一 启动
...one. Launch.
I. V. A. N.  请调出飞行计划
I.V.A.N., pull up the flight plan, please.
你好 我是你的内部 --
Hello. I am your internal--
自动导航仪
Autopilots.
你好 我是你的内部声控导航仪 请叫我I.V.A.N
Hello, I am your internal voice-activated navigator, call me I.V.A.N.
请准备好飞行计划 I.V.A.N
Ready the flight plan, please, I.V.A.N.
当然可以
Certainly.
你的任务是加速穿越深空
Your mission is to accelerate through deep space,
绕过阿尔法-特卡尼的弹弓
slingshot around Alpha T'Kani,
然后通过减速环回到塔卡尼主星这里
then through the deceleration rings back here to T'kani Prime.
目标飞行时间： 4分28秒
Target flight time: 4 minutes, 28 seconds.
XL-01 你可以进行超级发射了
XL-01, you are clear for hyper-launch.
收到 控制 启动超速发射
Copy, control. Initiating hyper-launch.
接近50%的超速
Approaching 50 percent hyper speed.
燃料稳定
Fuel stable.
将速度提高到0.6c
Increasing speed to 0.6c.
百分之六十的超速
Sixty percent hyper-speed.
增加速度至0.7c
Increasing speed to 0.7c.
百分之七十的超速
Seventy percent hyper-speed.
燃料稳定
Fuel stable.
接近0.8c
Approaching 0.8c.
推进到超速
Pushing to hyper-speed.
发动机1发生故障
Failure in Engine 1.
燃料电池不稳定
Fuel cell unstable.
I.V.A.N. 状态：
I.V.A.N., status.
轨迹错误 加四度
Trajectory error, plus four degrees.
如果不纠正航向将导致错过星环
Failure to course-correct will result in missing the rings.
我们会飞向深空
We'll fly off into deep space
导致必死无疑
resulting in certain death.
是的 谢谢你
Yes, thank you.
弹射是你唯一的选择
Ejection is your only option.
不 不 我可以做到
No, no. I can do it.
警告： 你有26秒的时间来纠正航线
Warning. You have 26 seconds to course-correct.
你现在有25秒的时间来纠正航向
You now have 25 seconds to course-correct.
-你现在有-- -请停止计数
-You now have-- -Stop counting, please.
我很抱歉 我的安全协议禁止我终止倒计时
I'm sorry. My safety protocols prohibit me from terminating countdown.
自动控制装置
Autopilots.
任务失败在即 请记录你的遗言
Mission failure imminent. Please record your last words.
今天不行 I.V.A.N.
Not today, I.V.A.N.
如果你对这个录音感到满意 请说话或选择1
If you are satisfied with this recording, speak or select 1.
I.V.A.N. 把引擎推到最大 最大功率
I.V.A.N., push the engines all the way. Maximum power.
这种行动是不可取的 燃料电池引爆 --
That action is inadvisable. Fuel cell detonation--
这正是我所期待的
Is exactly what I'm counting on.
情况危急
Situation critical.
燃料电池接近峰值容量
Fuel cell approaching peak capacity.
打开燃料门 I. V. A. N.
Open up the Fuel Door, I.V.A.N.
我很抱歉 我没有完全听清
I'm sorry. I didn't quite catch that.
-请重述你的命令 -打开燃料门！
-Please restate your command. -Open fuel door!
五分钟后引爆...
Detonation in five...
...四...
...four...
...三...
...three...
...二...
...two...
-... ...一 -现在！
-...one. -Now!
航线已纠正
Course corrected.
你没能达到超速
You failed to reach hyper-speed.
我不需要听到这个 I. V. A. N.
I didn't need to hear that, I.V.A.N.
你没听到？
You didn't hear that?
哦 我很抱歉 我再重复一遍
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll repeat.
-不 我听说--我是说-- -你没能达到超速
-No, I've heard-- I meant-- -You failed to reach hyper-speed.
-谢谢你 I. V. A. N. -你没能达到--
-Thank you, I.V.A.N. -You failed to reach--
指挥官 你还好吗？
Commander, are you okay?
迪亚兹 你长出了胡子
Diaz, you grew a beard.
你是怎么长出胡子的？
How did you grow a beard?
哦 对了
Oh, right.
首先 欢迎回来
First of, welcome back.
其次...
Secondly...
等等
Wait.
等等 这是什么？
Wait, what is this?
我离开多长时间了？
How long was I gone?
4年2个月零3天
Four years, two months and three days.
什么？
What?
我以为我们已经失去了你 巴兹
I thought we've lost you, Buzz.
艾莉莎 发生了什么事？
Alisha, what happened?
-时间膨胀 -什么？
-Time dilation. -What?
时间膨胀很简单
Time dilation is quite simple.
当你接近超速时 你的时间相对于我们的时间就变慢了
As you approached hyper-speed, your time slowed relative to our own.
所以 在你的任务中 你的年龄只有几分钟
So, during your mission you aged only minutes,
而我们其他人却老了很多年
while the rest of us have aged years.
简单地说：你飞得越快 --
Simply put: The faster you fly--
我飞得越快 我就越能穿越到未来
The faster I fly the further into the future I travel.
我明白了
I get it.
那么 我们现在要做什么呢？
So, what are we gonna do now?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我认为我们应该暂停更多的测试飞行
But I think we should hold off on any more test flights
直到我们想出别的办法
until we've figured out something else.
指挥官 我们说完成任务
Commander, we said finish the mission.
这就是太空游侠的工作
That's what Space Rangers do.
以什么为代价 巴兹？
At what cost, Buzz?
你愿意再损失四年时间吗？
Are you willing to lose another four years?
所以 大家只是被困在这里
So, everyone is just stuck here
因为我
because of me.
嘿 你没事吧？
Hey, you all right?
是的 是的 我很好
Yeah. Yeah. I'm fine.
等等 那是什么？
Wait, what's that?
哦 我订婚了
Oh, I got engaged.
哦 哇 那真是太好了 她叫什么名字？
Oh, wow. That's great. What's her name?
Kiko 她是科学小组的成员之一
Kiko. She's one of the science crew.
有趣的是 如果我们没有被搁浅 这根本就不重要
It's funny, it never would've mattered if we hadn't been stranded.
你和你刚认识的人订婚了？
You got engaged to someone you just met?
巴斯 我三年前就认识她了
Buzz, I met her three years ago.
哦 对 对
Oh, right. Right.
好吧 恭喜你 我很想见见她
Well, Congratulations. I'd love to meet her.
嗯 有足够的时间 休息一下吧
Well, there's plenty of time for that. Get some rest.
这是个命令
That's an order.
不客气！艾莉莎
YOU'RE WELCOME! ALISHA
你好 巴兹！
Hello, Buzz!
我是索克斯 你的私人伴侣机器人
I am Sox. Your personal companion robot.
我的什么？
My what?
我是星际指挥部派来的
I was issued by star command
来缓解你离开后的情绪变化
to ease your emotional transition after your time away.
哦 你考虑得真周到 机器猫
Oh, that's very considerate of you, robot feline.
不过不用了 谢谢你
But no thank you.
恐怕这是规定
I'm afraid it's protocol.
传感器显示你已经错过了四个生日
Sensors indicate you've missed four birthdays.
你想要一个磨砂零食套装来庆祝吗？
Would you like a frosted snack kit to celebrate?
不用了 那会影响到我的营养计划
Negative. That would compromise my nutritional regiment.
我们可以谈一谈你的感受 我是一个优秀的倾听者
We can talk about your feelings. I am an excellent listener.
不 不 听着 我有一个非常漫长的... ... 一天？
No, no. Look, I've had a very long... day?
它没有按计划进行
It did not go as planned.
任务不成功？
The mission was unsuccessful?
肯定的
Affirmative.
哦 不 我很抱歉听到这个消息
Oh, no. I am so sorry to hear that.
谢谢你 索克斯
Thank you, Sox.
不客气 巴兹
You're welcome, Buzz.
我们玩个游戏好吗？
Shall we play a game?
-不 谢谢你 -你确定吗？
-No, thank you. -Are you sure?
我可以根据你确切的性格特征 专门为你创造一个游戏
I can create a game specifically for you, based on your exact personality profile.
嘿 听着 索克斯 夥计 我很累了
Hey, listen, Sox, buddy, I'm pretty tired.
所以 我要先去打架了
So, I'm gonna go ahead and hit the rack.
当然了
Of course.
如果你愿意 我可以提供睡眠声音
I can provide sleep sounds if you like.
我有几个选择
I have several options.
夏天的夜晚 海洋的天堂 鲸鱼的叫声
Summer night, ocean ​​paradise, whale calls.
不 不 白噪音就可以了
No, no. White noise is fine.
很好
Very well.
-晚安 索克斯 -晚安 巴兹
-Good night, Sox. -Good night, Buzz.
拉起来
Pull up.
光年船长 你需要帮助吗？
Captain Lightyear, do you need help?
不 我可以的
No. I can do it.
巴斯 你确定吗？
Buzz, are you sure?
恐怕这是规定
I'm afraid it's protocol.
我可以的！
I can do it!
我可以做到的
I can do it.
审查员表示你做了个噩梦
Censors indicate you had a nightmare.
-你想谈谈它吗？-不愿意
-Would you like to talk about it? -Negative.
好的 但记住 我的任务是帮助你
Okay, but remember, my mission is to help you.
而且我不会放弃我的任务
And I'm not giving up on my mission.
是吗？
Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
你知道吗 索克斯 我也不会放弃我的任务
You know what, Sox, I'm not giving up on my mission either.
太好了！那我能做什么？
Great! So what can I do?
好吧 你为什么不和你的老鼠夥伴交往
Well, why won't you engage with your mouse buddy.
还有什么更有挑战性的吗？
Is there anything more challenging?
你想要挑战？好吧
You want a challenge? Okay.
我想你可以研究一下这个燃料稳定性的问题
I guess you could work on this fuel stability thing.
晶体聚变 当然了
Crystalic fusion. Of course.
我应该期待你什么时候回来？
When should I expect you back?
大约4年
About four years.
等一下 你没必要这样做
Hold on. You don't have to do this.
指挥官 这是我的错误
Commander, this is my mistake.
我需要把它纠正过来
I need to make it right.
好吧 但也许我们应该考虑一下这个
Okay, but maybe we should think about this.
考虑什么？来吧 我们是太空游侠
Think about what? Come on, we're Space Rangers.
我们要完成任务
We finish the mission.
好吧 这将是很好的再次穿上西装
Well, it would be nice to wear the suit again.
人们开始忘记太空游侠曾经的重要性
People are starting to forget Space Rangers ever mattered.
好吧 我正要解决这个问题
Well, I'm about to fix that.
到无限大
To infinity.
甚至更远
And beyond.
不稳定
UNSTABLE
40周年快乐
HAPPY 40TH ANNIVERSARY
不稳定
UNSTABLE
嗨 巴兹
Hi, Buzz.
你在一两年内回到这里...
You're back here in a year or two...
而且 我不会
and, well, I won't.
我不知道这是什么时候发生的
I don't know when it happened
但我似乎已经走了 变得很老了
but I seem to have gone and gotten very old.
我一直以为我们会再次成为太空游侠
I always thought we'd get to be Space Rangers again.
我怀念在星空中的日子
I miss being out among the stars.
所有的冒险
All the adventures.
但比起这些 我更想念
But more than any of that
我想念你
I missed you.
嗨 奶奶
Hi, Grandma.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, sweetheart.
我给我的朋友巴斯留个口信
I'm leaving a message for my friend, Buzz.
太空游侠？
The Space Ranger?
是的
That's right.
他是在太空中现在
He's in space right now.
哇
Wow.
这是我的孙女 Izzy
This is my granddaughter, Izzy.
我也要成为一名太空游侠
I'm gonna be a Space Ranger too.
就像他一样？
Just like him?
就像你一样
Just like you.
再见 巴斯
Goodbye, Buzz.
很抱歉我不能去看你完成任务了
I'm sorry I won't be there to see you finish the mission.
到无限大
To infinity.
还有更远
And beyond.
敲门 敲门 对不起 打扰了 我刚刚搬进我的新...
Knock. Knock. Sorry to interrupt. I'm just moving into my new-
看那！真正的巴斯光年在肉体上
Look at that! The actual Buzz Lightyear in the flesh.
肯定的
Affirmative.
指挥官卡尔-伯恩赛德
Commander Cal Burnside.
我小的时候是你的一个大粉丝
I was a big fan of your when I was a kid.
好吧 那么我期待着与你合作 最终让我们离开这里
Well, then I look forward to working with you to finally get us out of here.
没有人告诉你吗？
Did no one tell you?
告诉我什么？
Tell me what?
是的
Yeah.
那是最后的任务 巴兹
That was the last mission, Buzz.
什么？
What?
我们决定要继续留在这里
We've decided we gonna go ahead and stay right here.
等等 这里？不行 这不是一个可行的选择
Wait, here? Negative, that is not a viable option.
现在是了 看 我们正在建造这个
It is now. See, we're building this.
激光防护罩
Laser shield.
它可以把所有的人挡在外面
It'll keep all the creeters out.
我们就躲在这里 用我们拥有的东西来做
And we'll just tuck right in here and make do with what we've got.
凑合？不 等等 但你不明白 指挥官
Make do? No. Wait. But you don't understand, Commander.
我还是可以做到的 我可以让我们离开这里
I can still do it. I can get us outta here.
老兄 你还相信这一点 真是太好了
Man, it's great you still believe that.
但我们很好 巴兹
But we're good, Buzz.
得到了激光盾牌
Got the laser shield.
哦 你好 巴兹
Oh. Hello, Buzz.
巴斯？
Buzz?
我有个好消息 巴兹
Well, I've got some good news, Buzz.
我想出了燃料的问题
I figured out the fuel problem.
什么？
What?
这是一个有趣的组合
It was an interesting combination.
仅仅是最轻微的差异 但这就造成了所有的不同
Just the slightest variance, but that made all the difference.
索克斯 你是怎么做到的？
Sox, how did you do this?
我花了62年7个月又5天
It took me 62 years, seven months and five days.
而且它很稳定？
And it's stable?
理论上是的
Theoretically.
我期待着在你的下一次任务中找到答案
I look forward to finding out on your next mission.
是啊...
Yeah...
什么？
What?
晚上好 队长 我们是来接你的同伴机器人的
Evening, Captain. We're here to pick up your companion robot.
你是什么意思？
What do you mean?
安全目的 你明白的
Security purposes. You understand.
不 实际上 我不明白
No, actually, I don't.
关闭程序 所以 我们必须让你的猫退役
Shutting down the program, So, we have to decommission your cat.
这只需要一秒钟
It'll just take a second.
现在 等一下 只是...
Now, hold on, just...
至少让我来做
At least let me do it.
哇？
Whoa?
巴斯 我们要去哪里？
Buzz. Where are we going?
我们要去太空
We're going to space.
什么？
What?
巴斯光年的任务记录 星际约会...
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date...
我不知道
I have no idea.
在拥有稳定的燃料配方
In possession of stable fuel formula
我计划达到超速 这次终于完成了任务
I plan to reach hyper-speed and this time finally finish the mission.
你在和谁说话？
Who are you talking to?
无所谓了
Doesn't matter.
巴斯 我的程序迫使我通知星际指挥部你已经走了...
Buzz, my programming compels me to notify Star Command that you have gone--
星际指挥部打算让你退役
Star Command was gonna decommission you.
-什么？
-What? -That's right.
熄灯 没有索克斯了
Lights out. No more Sox.
嘿 你没有被授权进入这个区域
Hey! You're not authorized to be in this area--
哇 我不知道你能这么做
Whoa, I didn't know you could do that.
等一下 这是为我准备的 以防我越界？
Wait a minute, was that for me in case I got out of line?
我给你争取了5分钟
I bought you five minutes.
-好吧 索克斯 给我第一个 -罗杰
-All right, Sox, give me the first one. -Roger.
好了 开始吧
Okay, here it goes.
哇
Wow.
这个公式！
The formula!
探戈到基地 探戈到基地 发射架上的安全漏洞
Tango to Base. Tango to Base. Security breach in the launch peg.
爆炸
Blast.
我们有一个警卫倒下了 重复一遍 我们有一个警卫倒下了
We have a guard down. Repeat. We have a guard down.
好的
Okay.
你好
Hello.
-我是你的内部声控导航员 -不！I. V. A. N. ！不
-I'm your internal voice-activated navigator. -No! I.V.A.N.! No.
-你听到了吗？-叫我I.V.A.N
-Do you hear that? -Call me I.V.A.N.
任务控制中心 在XL-15探测到活动
Mission Control, activity detected in XL-15.
正在调查
Investigating.
收到
Roger that.
XL-15 这里是控制中心
XL-15, this is the control.
里面有人吗？
Is there someone in there?
-说说看 -XL-15
-Say something. -XL-15.
请回答
Please respond.
收到 控制室 只是... ... 清洁人员
Copy, control. Just... the cleaning crew.
我们正在清洁驾驶舱 清洁物品在这里？
We're cleaning the cockpit. Cleaning items in here?
指挥官 我们是否批准了XL-15的驾驶舱清洗工作？
Commander, did we authorize the cockpit cleaning for the XL-15?
什么？没有
What? No.
-停！回来！-等等！
-Stop! Come back! -Wait!
XL-15 你违反了星际指挥部的规定
XL-15, you are in violation of Star Command protocol.
立即停止你的行动
Cease your actions immediately.
打开这个舱门！
Open this hatch!
指挥官 我是光年船长
Commander, it's Captain Lightyear.
等等 什么？光年？把他救出来！
Wait? What? Lightyear? Get him out of there!
马上停下来 把你的手放在头上！
Stop right now and put your hands over your head!
往后退
Back up.
-我们需要后援 -让扎普巡逻队来
-We need back up. -Get the Zap patrol.
好了 队员们 我们走吧
All right, team. Let's go.
覆盖筒仓的门 他哪儿也不去
Override the silo doors. He isn't going anywhere.
爆炸
Blast.
未经授权
Unauthorized.
-未经授权 -来吧 我们在这里是坐以待毙
-Unauthorized. -Come on, we're sitting ducks here.
请允许我
Allow me.
-等等 发生了什么？-他推翻了我的超控
-Wait, what's happening? -He overrode my override.
怎么会？
How?
光年！
Lightyear!
我知道你能听到我
I know you can hear me.
马上把飞船送回基地!
Return the ship to base right now!
否则就帮我...
Or so help me--
索克斯 让我们打破这个超速障碍 带大家回家
Sox, let's break this hyper-speed barrier and get everyone home.
接近70%的超速
Approaching 70 percent hyper-speed.
接近80%的超速
Approaching 80 percent hyper-speed.
燃料稳定
Fuel stable.
90%的超速
Ninety percent hyper-speed.
百分之百的超速
One hundred percent hyper-speed.
恭喜你 光年船长
Congratulations, Captain Lightyear.
你已经实现了超速
You have achieved hyper-speed.
我们成功了 索克斯 我们成功了！
We did it. Sox, we did it!
恭喜你 巴斯
Congratulations, Buzz.
这真是太可怕了 我很后悔加入了你们
That was utterly terrifying, and I regret having joined you.
不 不
No, no.
怎么了 巴兹？
What is it, Buzz?
我们的速度仍然非常高
Our velocity is still extremely high.
什么？哦 不！
What? Oh no!
我们会坠毁吗？
Are we gonna crash?
不会
No.
嗯 技术上是的 撑下去吧
Well, technically yes. Just hang on.
经过这么多年的努力 谢谢你 索克斯
After all these years. Thank you, Sox.
任务记录 补充
Mission log, supplemental.
从星际指挥部借来一艘飞船后 我已经实现了超速
After borrowing a ship from Star Command I've achieved hyper-speed.
我已经准备好最终离开这个星球 一劳永逸
And I'm ready to finally leave this planet once and for all.
巴斯光年呼叫星际指挥部 请回话 星际指挥部
Buzz Lightyear to Star Command. Come in, Star Command.
星际指挥部 请回话
Star Command, come in.
他们为什么不回答？
Why don't they answer?
嘿！
Hey!
那些机器人
The robots.
什么？
The what?
机器人
The robots.
等等 它在做什么？
Wait, what's it doing?
Zurg.
-我的飞船！-安静点
-My ship! -Be quiet.
它去哪了？
Where'd it go?
在那上面
Up there.
祖尔格
Zurg.
飞行员在哪里？
Where is the pilot?
那是什么？发生什么事了？
What is that? What is going on?
蹲下
Get down.
射击！来吧
Shoot! Come on.
他们一定也看到了你的船登陆
They must have seen your ship land too.
-谁？-那些机器人
-Who? -The robots.
为什么会有机器人？机器人是从哪里来的？
Why are there robots? Where did the robots come from?
你从哪里来的？
Where did you come from?
我是从这里来的
I came from here.
在这里？等等
Here? Wait.
巴兹？
Buzz?
阿利沙？
Alisha?
哦 不 那是我的祖母 我是伊兹
Oh, no, that's my grandmother. I'm Izzy.
伊兹？
Izzy?
但你当时只是个小...
But you were just a little...
索克斯 我们离开多久了？
Sox, how long were we gone?
喵喵
Meow meow.
22年 19周又4天
Twenty-two years, 19 weeks and four days.
哇
Wow.
等等
Wait.
来吧
Come on.
在这里
In here.
我想我听到了一个
I thought I heard one.
-一个机器人？-是的
-A robot? -Yeah.
令人印象深刻
Impressive.
嗯 我是霍桑人
Well, I am a Hawthorne.
你当然是
You sure are.
你知道吗 你奶奶和我几乎可以完成对方的句子
You know, your grandma and I could practically finish each other's sentences.
如果你像她一样 你和我就会成为--
If you're anything like her, you and I are gonna make--
-...一个伟大的团队 -...有些机器人会哭
-...a great team. -...some robots cry.
好吧...
Okay...
所以 让我尽快了解这个
So, get me up to speed on this.
好的 Zurg飞船大约一周前出现了
Right. The Zurg ship showed up about a week ago.
什么是Zurg?
What's a Zurg?
机器人只说这个 所以我们就叫它大船
That's the only thing the robots say, so that's what we call the big ship.
Zurg飞船到了 机器人包围了基地 然后... ...
The Zurg ship arrived, the robots surrounded the base, and then...
T'kani主城的公民们 机器人外星人袭击了
Citizens of T'kani Prime, robot aliens have attacked.
每个人都在周边的范围内
Everyone inside the perimeter.
小心！
Look out!
我们立即启动激光防护罩
We are activating the laser shield immediately.
这就是我们最后听到的消息
And that's the last we heard.
所有这些人 他们都指望着我
All these people, they were counting on me.
而现在他们被困住了
And now they're trapped.
我们试图联系他们 但没有通信 不管是内部还是外部
We've tried to reach them, but there's no communication, in or out.
索克斯？
Sox?
喵喵 她是正确的
Meow meow. She's correct.
你把我和你的猫对上号了吗？
Did you check me against your cat?
嗯 他不是你的标准猫科动物
Well, he's not your standard-issue feline.
事实上 索克斯是你奶奶送的礼物
Actually, Sox was a gift from your grandmother.
-你好 Izzy -你好 索克斯
-Hello, Izzy. -Hello, Sox.
嘿 那是什么声音？来吧 别弄坏我的猫
Hey, what's that noise? Come on, don't break my cat.
他在打呼噜 他喜欢这样
He's purring. He likes it.
索克斯 你喜欢它吗？
Sox, do you like it?
我喜欢
I do.
好吧 我希望你已经准备好行动了 因为我们需要的是一个飞行员
Well, I hope you're ready for action. Because all we needed was a pilot.
为了什么？
For what?
我有一个计划 我有一个团队
I have a plan and I have a team.
来吧！
Come on!
好了 队员们 集合了
All right, team, fall in.
我找到了一个飞行员 惊喜派对行动已经开始了
I found a pilot. Operation Surprise Party is a go.
我喜欢这个 一个精锐的小队 最好的中的最好的
I like this. An elite squad. The best of the best.
你知道 她的祖母是军团历史上最伟大的太空游侠
You know, her grandmother was the greatest Space Ranger in the history of the Corps.
能和你一起工作将是一种荣誉
It will be an honor to work with you.
来吧 聚集在一起 团队
Come on, gather round, team.
让我们回顾一下我们的目标
Let's review our objectives.
杀死那些机器人
Kill the robots.
还有不要死
And don't die.
"不要死 "是你每天都想做的事情
"Don't die" is just something you wanna do every day.
这仍然是一个目标
It's still an objective.
如果我可以的话 我们有一个目标
If I may, we have one objective.
我们需要把这个水晶放进萝卜里 然后离开这里
We need to put this crystal in the turnip and get outta here.
所以 要做到这一点 我们必须进入基地
So, to do that we have to get onto the base.
要做到这一点 我们必须杀死所有的机器人
To do that we have to kill all the robots.
要做到这一点 我们必须摧毁Zurg的飞船
To do that we have to destroy the Zurg ship.
而要做到这些 我们就必须不死
And to do any of that we have to not die.
德里克
DERIC
请允许我解释一下 "惊喜派对 "行动
Allow me to explain Operation Surprise Party.
它是 "雷霆之矛 "行动的一个变种
It is a variation on Operation Thunder Spear.
你不是因为那次行动得到了一枚奖章吗？
Didn't you get a medal for that one?
实际上是两枚 但是...
Two, actually, but...
等等 你怎么知道 "雷霆之矛 "行动？
Wait, how do you know about Operation Thunder Spear?
我读过我奶奶所有的《太空游侠》书 从头到尾
I've read all my grandma's Space Ranger books, from cover to cover.
两次
Twice.
对不起 机器人猫咪
Excuse me, robot kitty.
哦 对不起
Oh, sorry.
感应器显示Zurg飞船为地面上的机器人提供动力
Sensors have indicated that the Zurg ship powers the robots on the ground.
所以 我们飞到那里 炸毁那艘船 惊喜吧 机器人！
So, we fly up there, we blow up the ship. And surprise, robots!
你被烤焦了
You're toast.
然后 我们把你的水晶放进萝卜里
Then, we put your crystal in the turnip.
然后完成任务
And finish the mission.
这是个好计划 为了无限大
It's a good plan. To infinity.
你想让我拉你的手指吗？
Are you trying to get me to pull your finger?
别上当了
Don't fall for it.
不 不是这样的 是...
No, not like that, it was...
对不起 这是你奶奶和我过去常做的事
Sorry, it's a thing your grandma and I used to do.
恶心
Ew.
我... ... 我们从来没有... ... 她不是故意...
I-- We were never-- She didn't mean to...
总之 忘了它 继续前进
Anyway, forget it. Moving on.
让我们把这些弹药装到犰狳号上
Let's load these munitions into the Armadillo
并为战斗做好准备
and steel ourselves for combat.
惊喜派对行动开始了
Operation Surprise Party is on.
巴兹 你听到了吗？
Buzz, do you hear that?
我听到一些声音
I hear something.
你认为是机器人吗？
You think it's a robot?
不 我们从来没有在离基地这么远的地方见过机器人
Nah, we've never seen a robot this far from the base.
我什么都没听到
I don't hear anything.
现在我听到了
Now I do.
Zurg.
别担心 我们会照顾你的
Don't worry, we got you.
什么？
What?
训练用的弹药
TRAINING AMMO
不要害怕！少年巡逻队支持你
Fear not! The Junior Patrol has your back.
少年什么？
The Junior what?
不 是飞船！
No! The ship!
我明白了吗？
Did I get it?
很接近
Pretty close.
对不起 我没有受过这种武器的训练
Sorry, I'm not trained with this weapon.
让我重新装弹
Let me reload.
没受过训练？等等 你说你 "没有受过训练 "是什么意思？
Not trained? Wait, what do you mean you're "not trained"?
你在那里 抓住它！抓住它！
You there. Grab it! Grab it!
抓住什么？
Grab what?
我不允许处理武器
I'm not allowed to handle weapons
这违反了我的假释规定
the violation of my parole.
假释？
Parole?
巴兹！
Buzz!
伊兹！现在！
Izzy! Now!
不！
No!
好吧 新的计划
Okay, new plan.
新计划？旧的计划是什么？
New plan? What was the old plan?
我需要... 有人看到鱼叉了吗？
I need the-- Anyone seen the harpoons?
他们预装了一个鱼叉 但我找不到... ...
They came preloaded with a harpoon, but I can't find--
哦 我找到了
Oh, I found it.
我找到了鱼叉 我现在要重新装上它 看看这个吧
I found the harpoons. I'm gonna reload it now. Check this out.
我找到了吗？
Did I get it?
往左一点
A little to the left.
什么？
What?
我拍到了吗？
Did I get it?
你得到了它
You got it.
是的！
Yes!
轰隆隆
Boom.
好吧 好吧 到底是什么... ... 那是怎么...
Okay, okay. What exactly-- How did that--
你们是谁？
Who are you?
我们是少年巡逻队 为你服务
We're the Junior Patrol, at your service.
对了 我需要更多信息
Right, I'm gonna need more information.
我们是一支由自我激励的学员组成的志愿者队伍
We are a volunteer team of self-motivated cadets.
我们每个月在前哨站这里训练一个星期
We train one week in a month here at the outpost.
莫、达比和我是上周末机器人出现时第一个到达的人
Mo and Darby and I were the first to arrive last weekend
当机器人出现的时候
when the robots showed up.
因此 我们策划了 "惊喜派对行动"
So, we cooked up Operation Surprise Party.
那么 你们是菜鸟？
So, you are rookies?
孩子 我们很想当菜鸟 还在为这个做准备
Boy, we'd love to be rookies, still building up to that.
好的 你们有弹药训练吗？
Okay. Do you have munitions training?
-部分 -战术训练？
-Partial. -Tactical engagement?
-待定 -战斗经验？
-Pending. -Combat experience?
是的！如果你算上我们刚刚经历的机器人情况
Yes! If you count the robot situation we just went through.
好的 来吧 索克斯
Okay. Come on, Sox.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
听着 你们看起来是好人
Look, you seem nice people.
我非常支持你们的训练计划
I'm very supportive of your training initiatives.
但我还是要继续下去 从这里开始
But I'm gonna go ahead and take it from here.
我们刚刚从那个机器人手里救了你
We just saved you from that robot.
-请问？-小莫打了一枪
-Excuse me? -Mo made the kill shot.
Mo很幸运
Mo got lucky.
非常
Very.
那么 如果你能给我指出另一艘飞船的方向
So, if you could just point me in the direction of another ship.
在废弃的储存库里有可操作的航天器
There are operational spacecrafts at the abandoned storage depot.
太好了 那是哪里？
Great. Where is that?
储存库直接与资源重组中心相邻
The storage depot is directly adjacent to the Resource Reconstituting Center,
距离你现在的位置有4.2公里
which is 4.2 kilometers from your current location.
很好 那是什么地方？
Great. Where is that?
这其实很简单
It's actually quite simple.
好吧
Okay.
你将首先向南朝基地走
You will first head south towards the base.
经过两个红绿灯后 你会...
After two stop lights you will--
等等 这是不对的 那是一个死胡同
Wait, that is not right. That is a dead end.
哦 我明白了 我走错地方了
Oh, I see, I was in the wrong spot.
对不起 我将重新开始
Apologies. I will start over.
你将首先向南走向基地
You will first head south towards the base.
过了两个红绿灯后 你会缓缓左转 然后... ...
After two stop lights you'll take a gentle left and--
说吧 我又犯了一个错误
Shoot. I have made another error.
我们就给你看看
We'll just show you.
请允许我重新开始
Allow me to restart.
你将首先向南走向基地
You will first head south towards the base.
过了两个红绿灯后 你会向右转弯...
After two stop lights you'll take a hard right...
巴斯光年补充任务日志
Buzz Lightyear supplemental mission log.
在终于实现了超速之后
Having finally achieved hyper-speed
现在我的道路上又多了一个障碍
I now have an additional obstacle in my way.
为了逃离这个星球 我必须独自摧毁一艘巨大的外星飞船
In order to flee this planet I'll have to destroy a massive alien ship alone.
而没有任何形式的援助
with no assistance of any kind.
你知道 我们可以帮助你 这是我们的计划
You know, we can help you. It is our plan.
我不能允许这样
I can't allow that.
Star Command Code 2709.3
3禁止我将不合格的人员置于危险境地
forbids me from placing unqualified personnel in harms way.
好吧 但我是霍桑人
Okay, but I'm a Hawthorne.
这不仅仅是一个名字 伊兹
It's more than just a name, Izzy.
你必须清楚地知道 --
You have to know exactly--
-在任何情况下如何反应... ...你接下来会说什么
-...how to react in any sit-- -...what you gonna say next.
我想我有这个能力
I thought I had that one.
好的
Okay.
而你 你是在某种教养情况下？
And you, you're in a correctional situation of some kind?
假释计划
Parole program.
我做这个 他们给我减了点刑
I do this and they shave a little time off my sentence.
但我在那里真的学到了很多东西
But I really learned a lot in there.
达比可以把任何三样东西 让它们爆炸
Darby can take any three things and make them explode.
好的 那你呢？ - 我？
Okay. And what about you?
我以为这将是一个有趣的新兵训练营锻炼的事情
Me? I thought this was gonna be like a fun boot camp workout thing.
但事实并非如此
But it is not.
所以 我实际上是来这里交出我的东西的 --
So, I was actually coming out here to turn in my stuff--
他是个放弃者
He's a quitter.
我不是放弃的人
I'm not a quitter.
你是辞职了
You were quitting.
你在说什么呢？我只是去了一个不同的方向
What are you talking about? I was just going in a different direction.
是的 一个放弃者的方向
Yeah, the direction of a quitter.
你知道吗 我放弃了
You know what, I give up.
-你看 在你的右边...
-See? -On your right..
祖格
Zurg.
现在 我说到哪里了？
Now, where was I?
我们到了 让我回去吧
Here we are. Let me back up.
嘿 继续练习你的技能 这是让你变得更好的唯一方法
Hey, keep working on your skills. It's the only way to get better.
我们可以帮助你
We can help you.
我也很感激 只要回到你的训练设施中去
And I appreciate that. Just go back to your training facility.
保持警惕 保持安全
Stay alert. Stay safe.
我要去征用这架P-32犰狳战斗机
I'm going to commandeer this P-32 Armadillo
然后去炸掉Zurg的船
and go blow up the Zurg ship.
那么 这只是告别？
So, this is just goodbye?
肯定的 再见
Affirmative. Goodbye.
对不起 我忘了我的猫
Sorry, I forgot my cat.
检测到生命体
Life forms detected.
它们是什么？
What are they?
巨大的昆虫类生物
Giant insectoid organisms.
这座建筑似乎是某种蜂巢
The building appears to be some sort of hive.
它们有威胁吗？
Are they a threat?
传感器显示它们正在冬眠
Sensors indicate they are hibernating.
非常好
Very good.
哦 看！
Oh, look!
那是XL -01
It's the XL-01.
已经很久没有...
It's been a long time since...
哇哦
Whoa.
这是什么？
What is it?
来吧 我给你看
Come on, I'll show you.
终于来了
Finally.
对不起 打断一下
Sorry to interrupt.
看起来你正在享受一个真正美好的时刻
Looks like you were having a real nice moment.
你在这里做什么？这不安全
What are you doing here? It's not safe.
你拿了我们卡车的钥匙
You took the keys to our truck.
他们在那里
There they are.
来吧 来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
-安静 -我正在努力
-Quiet. -I'm trying.
明白了
Got it.
-谁去... ... -去开门！
-Somebody get-- -Get the door!
你想说 "开门" 而我已经开门了
You were gonna say "get the door", and I got the door.
好吧 我就直说了吧 我希望这事没有发生
Well, I'm gonna be blunt here. I wish that hadn't happened.
我们其他人也是如此
So did the rest of us.
每个人都拿起武器
Everyone grab a weapon.
孩子 我也想 但我的假释... ...
Boy, I'd love to, but my parole--
作为一名星际指挥官 我授予你紧急权力
As a Star Command Officer I grant you emergency authority.
我们要用爆炸的方式离开这里
We're gonna blast our way outta here.
现在我们正在谈论！
Now we're talking!
巴斯 正面攻击的生存概率是38. 2%
Buzz, the probability of survival a frontal attack is 38.2 percent.
似乎有点低
Seems a bit low.
那隐身模式呢？
What about Stealth Mode?
你怎么知道隐身模式的？
How do you know about Stealth Mode?
祖母和我过去一直在玩隐身模式
Grandma and I used to play Stealth Mode all the time.
这就像捉迷藏 但有一个转折
It was like hide-and-seek, but with a twist.
好吧 其实这是很好的想法 我将使用隐身模式来迷惑他们
Okay, well, it's actually good thinking. I'll use Stealth Mode to disorient them.
或者 在这里坚持我的观点
Or, and stick with me here.
我们都可以使用隐身模式 直接走出去
We could all use Stealth Mode and just walk right out.
你是说 你会穿上太空游侠的衣服？
You mean, you would wear a Space Ranger suit?
这套衣服上已经有我的名字了
This one already has my name on it.
好的
Okay.
让我们回顾一下
Let's review.
我去...
I'm going--
那边走
That way.
而你要去...
And you're going--
那边
That way.
好的 非常好
Okay. Very good.
看看吧 我是羽毛... 羽毛... ...
Check it out, I'm Feathers... Feathering...
哦 看 一支笔 真酷
Oh, look, a pen. Cool.
-你的有笔吗？-好了 注意了
-Does yours have a pen? -Okay, pay attention.
隐身模式是相当简单的
Stealth mode is fairly simple.
只有两个部分 你按下这个按钮--
There are just two parts. You press the button--
-是这个按钮吗？-我会告诉你哪个按钮
-Is it this button? -I will tell you which button.
-那这个按钮呢？-我很抱歉
-What about this button? -I'm sorry.
我们没有时间去看所有的按钮了
We're not gonna have time to go over all the buttons.
好吧 忘了这个按钮 那这个东西呢？
Okay, forget the button. What about this thing?
-它更-- -不！不！ 不！
-It's more-- -No! No!
那是投降线 你千万别拉那个
That's the surrender strand. You never pull that.
对于太空游侠来说 没有比这更可耻的举动了
There is no more shameful maneuver for a Space Ranger.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我是不是错过了哪个按钮是隐身模式的按钮？
Did I miss which button is the Stealth Mode button?
是这个按钮
It's this button.
还不行！
Not yet!
你按下这个按钮 然后你就从前门出去
You push this button, then you go out the front door,
然后我就去炸掉Zurg的船
and I'll go blow up the Zurg ship.
-准备好了吗？-准备好了
-Ready? -Ready.
不 等等 还没准备好 等一下
No, wait. Not ready. Hang on.
好了 搞定他们了 这将一直是尴尬的
Okay, got 'em. That would've been embarrassing.
好的
Okay.
再见了
Goodbye again.
索克斯 你抑制了我的视觉
Sox, you're inhibiting my visual.
对不起 这样好些了吗？
Sorry. Is this better?
-不对 -好吧 这个怎么样？
-Negative. -Okay, how about this?
这样如何？
How about this?
好的 我们开始吧
Okay. Here we go.
非常好 隐形模式按计划进行
Very good. Stealth Mode working as planned.
这真是太酷了 这些愚蠢的虫子甚至不能看到我们
This is pretty cool. These dumb bugs can't even see us.
嘿 虫子 嘿 虫子 虫子
Hey, bug. Hey, bug. Bug.
我就在这里 虫子 你看不到我吗？
I'm right here, bug. Can't you see me?
他不能 他根本就看不到我
He can't. He can't see me at all.
而且时间已经过了
And time has elapsed.
等等 定时器
Wait, the timer.
他们不知道定时器
They don't know about the timer.
你没有看到我
You don't see me.
等等 我可以看到你
Wait. I can see you.
我也能看到你
I can see you too.
虫子们能看到我们
The bugs can see us.
不 不 我投降了
No, no. I surrender.
拉！
Pull!
后退！后退！
Back! Back!
这不管用
This isn't working.
你必须继续前进！
You have to keep going!
我们必须掉头
We have to turn around.
他们正朝我们走来
They're headed right for us.
不 不 不要靠近那辆车！
No, no. Do not approach the vehicle!
好的！
All right!
-适应的方式 团队 -在这里交出它
-Way to adapt, team. -Give it up here.
你们为什么要祝贺自己？
Why are you congratulating yourselves?
因为我刚刚把我们从那种情况下山楂出来了
Because I just Hawthorned us out right outta that situation.
但你本可以做到的 如果...
But you could've made it if--
如果你告诉我们隐身模式会失效
If you had told us the Stealth Mode wears off.
好吧...
Well...
好了 大家系好安全带
Okay, everyone just strap in.
你好 我是你的...
Hello, I am your--
等一下！
Hold on!
我们要去太空吗？
Are we going to space?
不 我要把你放在某个地方
No, I'm gonna drop you somewhere.
这是个大漩涡 我想我需要一个袋子
That was a big swirly turn. I think I need a bag.
不 不 不要在车内呕吐
No, no. Do not vomit inside the vehicle.
我可以看到开始 那是空间
I can see starts. That is space.
现在是什么情况？
What is happening right now?
她害怕空间
She's afraid of space.
-什么？ -她应该是 太可怕了
-What? -She should be. It's horrible
伊兹 记住你的练习
Izzy, remember your exercises.
-它要来了 -不 不
-It's coming. -No, no.
把你的头盔接合起来 那会抓住它的
Engage your helmet. That will catch it.
-嗡嗡声！另一艘飞船！-伊兹 我正在努力... ...
-Buzz! Another ship! -Izzy, I'm trying--
我什么都看不见了
I can't see anything.
哦 不！地球的黑暗面
Oh, no! The dark side of the planet.
在那里！三点钟方向！
Over there! Three o'clock!
坚持住 这不会是件好事
Hold on. This isn't gonna be pretty.
大家都还好吗？
Is everyone okay?
我想是的
I think so.
索克斯 给我一份损害报告
Sox, give me a damage report.
请稍等
One moment, please.
好的 这样就好了
Okay. This is better.
这是更好吗？
Is this better?
不 显然这是更糟糕的整体 我只是意味着... 你知道...
No, obviously this is worse overall, I just meant... You know...
你怎么会害怕太空？
How are you afraid of space?
哦 这很容易
Oh, It's pretty easy.
你知道吗 如果你在外面放任自流 你就会一直朝着同一个方向前进
Did you know if you let go out there you just keep going in the same direction
永远 只是...
forever, just...
好吧 那你打算怎么炸掉Zurg的船？
Well, then how were you going to blow up the Zurg ship?
我本来是做地面支援的
I would've been ground support.
我知道 奶奶并不害怕太空
I know, grandma wasn't afraid of space.
不 因为她是一名太空游侠
No, because she was a Space Ranger.
天体恐惧症是自动取消资格的
Astrophobia is an automatic disqualification.
那是什么东西？
What was that thing?
-我不知道 -它还会回来吗？
-I don't know. -Is it gonna come back?
我不知道
I don't know.
但它是怎么... ... 好吧 你不知道
But how did it-- Okay, you don't know.
我已经完成了 我终于拿到了水晶 这本来应该结束的
I was done. I finally had the crystal. This was supposed to be over.
但我在骗谁呢？
But who am I kidding?
我不需要水晶
I don't need a crystal.
我需要一台时间机器来摆脱这种混乱
I need a time machine to get out of this mess.
评估完成
Assessment complete.
这有多糟？
How bad is that?
爆炸被挡热板吸收了 只造成了轻微的电气短路
The blast was absorbed by the heat shield and only caused a minor electrical short.
好的
Okay.
那么 为了能在飞行中使用
So, in order to be flight operational
犰狳需要一种特殊电容的材料
the Armadillo will require a material of specialized capacitance.
哦 就像一个电气的东西
Oh, like an electrical thingy.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know that?
我们学过这个
We learned this.
专门的电容 记得吗？我们上个月做了那些野外收音机？
Specialized capacitance, remember? We built those field radios last month?
哦 是的 那很有趣
Oh, yeah. That was fun.
是的 除了达比把她的弄乱了
Yeah, except Darby messed hers up.
我要把你弄得一团糟 --
I'm gonna mess you up--
拜讬了 我正在努力思考
Please. I'm trying to think here.
我把我的弄乱了 但我又把它修好了
I messed mine up, but then I fixed it up.
但是你弄坏了那个电脑控制台
But you broke that computer console.
我需要那个小线圈来... 那是什么？
I needed that little coil for its... What was that?
专门的电容
Specialized capacitance.
嘿 说实话 这里有很多空间
Hey, honestly, there is a lot of room out here.
如果你们想回忆一下 你们可以到那边去
If you guys wanna reminisce you could go over there,
或者看 那里没有人想去思考
or look, there's no one trying to think over there.
我们可以到上面去
We can go up there.
好吧 完美
Fine. Perfect.
是的 好的 新计划
Yes. Okay, new plan.
等等 什么？
Wait. What?
那个采矿设施会有一个控制台 对吗？
That mining facility will have a console, right?
那个控制台会有一个小线圈 对吗？
That console will have a little coil thing, right?
而那个小线圈的东西会有...
And that little coil thing will have the...
专门的电容
Specialized capacitance.
我们需要修复这艘船 对吗？
That we need to fix this ship, right?
她是对的
She's right.
做得好 这就是霍桑人的思维方式
Good job. Now that's thinking like a Hawthorne.
我们去拿那个零件 然后离开这里吧
Let's go get that part and get outta here
在那东西再次找到我们之前
before that thing finds us again.
哇
Whoa.
在那边
Over there.
好了 我们走吧
Okay, here we go.
巴斯光年任务日志
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
为了修复我们的飞船 我们必须找到一些方法
In order to repair our ship we have to find some way
进入指挥中心并...
to get inside the Command Center and...
干得好 老犯人
Nice job, elderly convict.
好的 激活线圈应该在这里
Okay, the activation coil should be in here.
索克斯？
Sox?
需要一支笔吗？
Need a pen?
知道了
Got it.
好的 是的 再来一次
Okay, yeah. Another time.
哦 不
Oh no.
安全措施启动
Security measures activated.
不 不能再这样了
No! Not this again.
不是什么？这是什么？
Not what? What is this?
一个捕获锥 在他们来抓你之前 它能把你关起来
A capture cone. That holds you until they come and get you.
没有人会来救我们 他们都被困在基地里了
No one's coming to get us. They're all trapped in the base.
所以 我们应该离开 对吗？
So, we should just leave, right?
我们不能就这样离开
We can't just leave.
当然 我们可以 听我说 我们总是可以离开的
Sure we can. Take it from me, we can always just leave.
看 看到了吗？
Look, see?
来吧！
Come on!
我告诉过你
Told you.
现在 要小心 因为这些东西 --
Now, be careful, because these things--
如果它们碰在一起 就会结合起来
combine if they touch.
好吧 对不起 但也许如果我们两个都试一下？
All right, sorry. But maybe if we both try it?
那是不可能的
That's not gonna work.
你甚至都没试过
You haven't even tried.
不！
No!
喵喵
Meow.
是的 那没有用
Yeah, that didn't work.
-巴兹？-哇 坚持住
-Buzz? -Whoa, hold on.
如果我和你一起被困在那里 我对任何人都没有帮助
I'm no help to anyone if I'm stuck in there with you.
索克斯 你能把这些关掉吗？
Sox, can you turn these off?
我够不到控制装置
I can't reach the controls.
等等 这里的地板上有个软点
Wait, there's a soft spot in the floor here.
-也许我们可以... ... -那是我的脚
-Maybe if we could-- -That's my foot.
-对不起 -等等 小心！
-Sorry. -Wait, watch it!
等等 就是这个 那东西给这些东西提供了动力
Wait, that's it. That thing powers these things.
-那我们就再打一次 -等等 等一下
-Then let's hit it again. -Wait. Wait.
我们需要门是开着的
We need the door to be open.
那么我就打开这个 你猛地撞上电源
So I'll open this. You slam into the power source.
这些东西会消失 然后我们就可以走出去了
These things will disappear. And we'll walk right out.
-是的 先生 -好的
-Yes, sir. -All right.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
继续努力！
Keep trying!
我们只是不够重
We're just not heavy enough.
巴斯 我们需要你
Buzz, we need you.
等等 在那里？
Wait, in there?
但如果不成功 我就不能救你们了
But if it doesn't work I won't be able to save you.
你不需要救我们 你需要加入我们
You don't need to save us, you need to join us.
再来
Again.
再来！
Again!
不！
No!
走！快走！
Go! Go!
小心点！
Watch out!
巴斯 不要！
Buzz, no!
我们需要线圈
We need the coil.
我们得到了你
We got you.
哦 看 零食
Oh, look. Snacks.
有人要吃零食吗？
Anyone going for the snack?
肉类三明治
MEAT SANDWICH
这里 让我们都再充点电吧
Here. Let's all re-charge a little.
给你
Here you go.
嗯 这是 呃--什么--什么--
Huh, this is, uh-- What-- What's--
这里发生了什么？
What's happening here?
你的三文治有问题吗？
Something wrong with your sandwich?
为什么肉在外面？
Why is the meat on the outside?
因为它是一个三明治？
Because it's a sandwich?
不 面包应该是在外面的
No, the bread is supposed to be on the outside.
什么 比如 面包 肉 面包？
What, like, bread, meat, bread?
那是太多的面包了
That's too much bread.
是的 但这都是湿的
Yes, but this is all wet.
是的 多汁的手指 那是最好的部分
Yeah. Juicy fingers. That's the best part.
你上次吃三明治是什么时候？
When was the last time you had a sandwich?
我不知道 一百年前 差不多吧
I don't know, a hundred years ago, give or take.
只是一个 "面包 肉 面包"
Just a "bread, meat, bread."
那是太多的面包了
That's too much bread.
那会把你嘴里的水分都吸走的
That would just suck all the moisture out of your mouth.
说得好 达比
Good one, Darby.
哦 不！
Oh, no!
索克斯！
Sox!
醒醒吧 索克斯
Wake up, Sox.
来吧 小家伙 回到我身边
Come on, little buddy, come back to me.
求你了 索克斯 我很抱歉
Please, Sox. I'm sorry.
索克斯
Sox.
你好 我需要重启
Hello. I require a reboot.
我很抱歉 夥计们 我差点杀了索克斯
I'm sorry, guys. I almost killed Sox.
我差点把我们都害死了 在那里
I almost got us all killed back there.
嘿 听我说 这只是一个错误
Hey, listen to me, it was just a mistake.
对吧 巴兹？
Right, Buzz?
试着让自己变得更好一点
Just try to get a little better.
听着
Listen.
我只是...
I just...
当我第一次去学院的时候 我并不... 你知道... 好
When I first went to the Academy I was not... you know... good.
我每天都搞砸了
I screwed up every day.
我在障碍赛中被缠住了
I got tangled in the obstacle course.
我的手抖得厉害 无法打中目标
My hands shook so much I couldn't hit the target.
不是指牛眼 是整个目标
Not the bulls-eye. The whole target.
第一周后 我打算退出 因为... ...
And I was gonna quit after the first week, it was...
显然我不是太空游侠的料
clear I was not Space Ranger material.
真的吗？
Really?
是的
Yeah.
但她的祖母在我身上看到了一些东西
But her grandma saw something in me.
所以我也开始寻找它
So I started looking for it too.
重新校准
Recalibrating.
一个损坏的文件恢复了
One corrupted file restored.
嘿 他亮了
Hey, he's lighting up.
-奶奶 -你好 索克斯
-Grandma. -Hello, Sox.
我需要你帮我一个忙
I need you to do me a favor.
我需要你照顾我最好的朋友 他的名字叫巴兹
I need you to look after my best friend. His name is Buzz.
他现在不在 但他很快就会回来
He's away right now, but he'll be back soon.
他是一名太空游侠
He's a Space Ranger.
他要把我们都带回家 让我们都回家
He's going to get us all home. Get us all home.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
你没听到吗？
Did not you hear that?
她相信我可以弥补我犯的错误
She believed I could fix the mistake I made.
而这种信念让她失去了一切
And that belief cost her everything.
一切？不是
Everything? No.
她有基科奶奶 我爸爸和我 她所有的朋友
She had grandma Kiko, my Dad and me, all her friends.
她本不应该在这里 但她在这个星球上有一个完整的生命 巴兹
She didn't meant to be here, but she had a whole life on this planet, Buzz.
我们所有人都有
All of us had.
除了你
Except for you.
我们想再次成为太空骑兵 我们想成为重要人物
We wanted to be Space Rangers again. We wanted to matter.
相信我 她很重要
Believe me, she mattered.
你知道 这样很好
You know, it is pretty good this way.
是吗？面包 肉 面包 你这样做了多长时间？
Yeah? Bread, meat, bread. How long did you do it like that?
永远
Forever.
完全充电
Fully recharged.
来吧
Come on.
我们去把这部分放到船上 然后离开这里
Let's go put this part in the ship and get outta here.
索克斯 你能照亮我们的路吗？
Sox, can you light our way?
当然可以
Of course.
卡嚓 卡嚓
Click click. Click click.
我看到你了 我要抓住你 我要抓住你
I see you. I'm gonna get ya. I'm gonna get ya.
哦 我没有得到你
Oh, I didn't get ya.
-索克斯？-你去哪了？我抓住你了！
-Sox? -Where'd you go? I got you!
-索克斯 -是的 对不起
-Sox. -Yeah, sorry.
这真是令人兴奋 惊喜派对行动 我们来了！
This is exciting. Operation Surprise Party, here we come!
等等 什么？负面的 我不能让你这样处于危险境地
Wait, what? Negative. I can't put you in harm's way like that.
什么 你要独自完成整个任务吗？
What, are you gonna do the whole mission alone?
我可以做到
I can do it.
因为你有一个霍桑 就在这里
Because you got a Hawthorne right here.
我很感激 告诉你 如果我需要你 我会让你知道
And I appreciate that. Tell you what, I'll let you know if I need you.
但在那之前 我们先设法回到犰狳号 不要再...
But until then let's just try to get back to the Armadillo without any more--
快跑！
Run!
不！
No!
什么？
What?
它在追我！回到船上去！
It's after me! Go back to the ship!
但是巴斯！
But Buzz!
巴斯光年任务日志
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
我被一个...
I'm being pursued by a...
只是一个巨大的机器人
just a massive robot.
我把它引开 而其他人则逃到船上去
I'm leading it away while the others escape to the ship.
巴斯 -什么？
Buzz.
什么 你怎么知道我的名字？
What? How do you know my name?
跟我过来
Come with me.
什么？
What?
这绝对是违反了我的假释规定
This is definitely a violation of my parole.
来吧 让我们离开这里
Come on. Let's get outta here.
Zurg.
准备好发射 惊喜派对行动又开始了
Ready yourselves for launch. Operation Surprise Party is back on.
什么？和我们一起？
What? With us?
什么？ 我一个人完成整个任务吗？
What, am I gonna do  the whole mission alone?
我们还不能发射  我需要5分钟来安装线圈
We can't launch yet.  I need five minutes to install the coil.
我们不能在这里坐5分钟
We can't sit here for five minutes.
这艘船仍有悬停能力
The ship still has hover capabilities.
那我们就用它们吧
Then let's use them.
我们可能会在火焰喷泉中失去它们
We might lose them in the fire geysers.
眨眼的方式 你们两个 炸掉一些机器人
Blink the way. You two, blast some robots.
但我们甚至还没有完成弹药训练
But we haven't even finished  our munitions training.
这能有多难？你看
How hard can it be? Look.
我们有这些带刺的东西  而这些东西可能会爆炸
We got these spiky things.  And these one probably explode.
只要做任何感觉正确的事
Just do whatever feels right.
什么？你打算怎么做？
What? What are you gonna do?
我要和 "轰隆先生 "跳舞
I'm gonna dance with Mister Boom.
这下可满意了
Now that's satisfying.
完成了百分之二十
Twenty percent complete.
一百箇中的一个？
Out of a hundred?
他们在追赶我们 那些喷火器在哪里？
They're gaining on us. Where are those fire geysers?
就在前面
Dead ahead.
别担心 我知道每一寸的...
Don't worry,  I know every last inch of--
小心点！
Watch out!
这里 扔这个
Here, throw this.
-等等 坚持住 -扔了它！
-Wait, hold on. -Throw it!
Zurg.
火焰喷泉正前方！
Fire geyser dead ahead!
完成了百分之五十
Fifty percent complete.
祖格
Zurg.
嘿 我们这里有炸药！
Hey, we have explosives back here!
快！给我点东西
Quick! Give me something.
祖格
Zurg.
完成了百分之九十
Ninety percent complete.
伊兹 你知道如何在飞行中转移动力吗？
Izzy, do you know how to transfer  power on the fly?
我已经在模拟器上做过了
I've done it in the simulator.
好吧 现在要来真的了
Well, it's about to get real.
-你需要我帮忙吗？-绝对不需要
-Do you need my help with anything? -Absolutely not.
完成了百分之九十五
Ninety five percent complete.
推进器准备就绪 绿色按钮 中间
Ready thrusters. Green button. Middle.
完成了
Done.
记住训练中的内容
Remember from training.
你不要扣动扳机 你要捏住扳机
You don't pull the trigger,  you squeeze the trigger.
我知道
I know.
完成百分之九十九
Ninety nine percent complete.
转移到震荡动力
Transfer to Oscillating Power.
完成了
Done.
百分之百完成
One hundred percent complete.
重新启动 好的 准备好发射
Reboot. Okay, be ready to launch
当燃料电池...
when the fuel cell is--
不！
No!
哦 不
Oh, no.
爆炸！
Blast!
抓住水晶！
Grab the crystal!
不 不
No.
I...
巴兹
Buzz.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
一切都发生得太快了 我...
Everything was happening so fast and I...
我只是...
I just...
我犯了一个错误
I made a mistake.
是的
Yeah.
好吧 但我们还没有完成 对吗？
Okay, but we're not done, right?
我们仍然可以做一些事情
We can still do something.
伊兹 看看周围
Izzy, look around.
没有什么可做的
There is nothing to do.
这个任务...
The mission...
已经结束了
It's over.
巴斯
Buzz.
巴斯！
Buzz!
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
我只是需要一个人静一静
I just need to be by myself.
不！
No!
巴斯！
Buzz!
Buzz.
这是什么...
What the...
这是什么？我们在哪里？
What is this? Where are we?
你是谁？
Who are you?
这就是问题所在
Now that's the question.
你看起来不错 巴兹
You look good, Buzz.
爸爸？
Dad?
再猜猜看
Guess again.
索克斯？
Sox?
你好 巴兹
Hello, Buzz.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我把这一切都搞砸了
I messed this all up.
嘿 这只是一个错误
Hey, it was just a mistake.
还记得你告诉我的吗？
Remember what you told me?
这一次是不同的
This one's different.
为什么？
Why?
因为这是我的！
Because it's mine!
我应该和我奶奶一样好
I'm supposed to be as good as my grandma.
我应该是霍桑的人
I'm supposed to be a Hawthorne.
但我不是
But I'm not.
巴兹？
Buzz?
等一下 等一下
Wait a minute, hold on.
你不是我 我是我
You're not me. I am me.
你现在是你
You are you now.
但我是50年后的你
But I'm you 50 years from now.
好吧 不可能有两个MES
Well, there can't be two mes.
但我们都在这里
Yet here we both are.
那么好吧 如果你是我
Okay then. If you're me.
我在想一个介于1和 --
I'm thinking of a number between one and--
1273.
哇哦
Whoa.
祖格
Zurg.
这不是很可爱吗？
Isn't that cute.
机器人不能完全说 "嗡嗡"
Robots can't quite say "Buzz."
所以在这里我就叫祖格
So around here I'm just Zurg.
扎克
Zurg.
我想你也是
And I guess so are you.
怎么会呢？我不明白
How? I don't understand.
不要担心 这一切都不重要了
Do not worry about it. None of this is gonna matter.
巴兹
Buzz.
什么事？
Yes?
你必须向他解释这一切
You have to explain it all to him.
你是对的
You're right.
我很抱歉 这只是令人兴奋
I'm sorry, it's just exciting.
你终于来了
You're finally here.
看 我也达到了超速
See, I reached hyper-speed too.
超速
Hyper-speed.
和你一样
Like you did.
但我没有被当作英雄来迎接
But I wasn't greeted as a hero.
不 那个新指挥官要以偷窃XL-15的罪名逮捕我
No, that new Commander was gonna  arrest me for stealing the XL-15.
我找到了一个让他们回家的方法 而他们甚至都不在乎
I'd found a way to get them home, and they didn't even care.
所以我逃了出来
So I escaped.
我尽可能地走得远 尽可能地快
I went as far as I could, as fast as I could.
以这种速度走了那么久 我已经走了几个世纪
At that speed for that long I'd traveled centuries.
而我最终来到了一个你不认识的未来
And I ended up in a future you wouldn』t recognize.
充满了你无法想像的技术
Filled with technology you can't imagine.
就在那时 我恍然大悟
And that's when it dawned on me.
如果我们能用这块水晶向前推进时间
If we can use this crystal  to go forward in time.
为什么不能用它来回到过去呢？
Why not use it to go back?
但我们不能回到过去
But we can't go back in time.
-我们现在可以 -什么？
-We can now. -What?
听着 巴兹 我已经打破了时间
Listen, Buzz, I've broken time.
发生在你身上的事从未发生在我身上
What's happening to you never happened to me.
这是个全新的现在 从来没有过的
This is a new now that's never been lived.
你看 我们可以改变事情 巴兹
You see, we can change things, Buzz.
如果我们能回到过去 我们可以阻止自己
Well, if we can go back in time  we can stop ourselves
我们可以阻止自己降落在那个星球上
from ever landing on that planet.
不去撞上那座山
From ever hitting that mountain.
我们可以继续完成回家的任务
We can just continue the mission home.
而这一切都不会发生
And none of this will have ever happened.
这是个好计划
it's a good plan.
而这个水晶是这一切的关键
And this crystal is the key to it all.
等等 你不是已经有一个了吗？
Wait, don't you already have one?
嗯 算是吧
Well, sort of.
你看 在测试时间旅行时 我把我的水晶磨光了
See, I wore my crystal out testing the time travel.
也把自己累坏了 花了不少时间
Wore myself out too. It took a while.
结果发现这并不是一门精确的科学
Turns out this isn't an exact science.
这是我能得到的最远的时间了
This is as far back in time  as I could get.
来吧 帮我配置引擎
Come on, help me configure the engine.
它应该看起来很熟悉
It should look familiar.
等等 这是基于萝卜吗？？
Wait, is this based on the turnip?
把它设定为反转推进器 全速前进
Set it for reversed thrusters, full.
那么 这些都是我们设计的？
So, we designed all of this?
不 这都是借来的
No, this is all borrowed.
我只是做了一些修改
I just made some modifications.
她又可以当太空游侠了 巴兹
She'll get to be  a Space Ranger again, Buzz.
是啊 虽然...
Yeah.
虽然...
Although...
什么？
What?
嗯 她将不会有她的家人
Well, she won't have her family.
她不会有伊兹了
She won't have Izzy.
谁是Izzy?
Who's Izzy?
听着 她不会想念任何人
Look, she's not gonna miss anyone
如果她一开始就没有遇到他们 对吗？
if she never meets them  in the first place, right?
人们唯一会知道的是我们完成了我们的任务
The only thing people are gonna know  is that we finished our mission.
给你 把你的水晶递给我
Here. Hand me your crystal.
巴兹？
Buzz?
我不知道 也许...
I don't know, maybe...
也许我们应该考虑一下这个
maybe we should think about this.
考虑什么？
Think about what?
霍桑指挥官相信我们可以弥补我们犯下的这个错误
Commander Hawthorne believed  we could fix this mistake we made.
而这种信念使她失去了一切
And that belief cost her everything.
哦 不 不 我们完全搞错了
Oh, no, no. We had that all wrong.
她在下面有一个完整的生活
She had a whole life down there.
什么样的生活？
What kind of life?
我们应该是太空游侠
We're supposed to be Space Rangers.
我们应该是重要的
We suppose to matter.
你不会想这样生活的 巴兹
You don't wanna live like this, Buzz.
在同样的恶梦中醒来
Waking up with that same nightmare.
被你的错误所困扰
Haunted by your mistake.
但你终于可以放手了
But you can finally let go of that.
从现在开始
Starting right now.
你是对的
You're right.
我可以
I can.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
你和我 我们是不一样的
You and me, we're not the same.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不 巴兹
No, Buzz.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
嘿 猫
Hey, cat.
你知道怎么开这个东西吗？
Do you know how to fly this thing?
没有燃料了
There's no fuel.
你看 这就是为什么我们不应该在我们的头顶上得到
See, this is why we should  never have gotten in over our heads.
你想做什么？
What did you wanna do?
在前哨站等着机器人找到我们？
Wait at the outpost  until the robots found us?
这总比被困在这里好吧？
That's better  than being stranded out here.
总比被困在没有人会找到我们的地方要好
where no one's ever gonna find us.
你是我最不想在生死关头与之为伍的人
You are the last person I wanna be  stuck with in a life-and-death situation.
好吧 你很幸运 好吗？
Well, you're in luck. Okay?
因为看看周围  这只是一个死亡的情况
Cause look around.  This is just a death situation.
喵喵
Meow meow.
我已经完全失去了巴兹
I've completely lost Buzz.
他离得太远了 无法追踪
He's too far away to track.
各位 进去！
Everybody, inside!
什么？
What?
快进船舱
Get inside the ship.
现在是什么在追我们？
What's after us now?
我们没有任何武器了
We don't have any more weapons.
没事了 我们要离开这里了
It's okay. We're getting out of here.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
我们要进入太空
We're going into space.
嘿 放开我 不！
Hey, let go of me. No!
我不明白这里发生了什么 巴兹
I don't understand  what's happening here, Buzz.
你已经改变了
You've changed.
而且不是往好的方面发展
And not for the better.
不！
No!
你不能这样做  你要把这一切都抹掉
You can't do this.  You're gonna erase it all.
是的
Exactly.
不 你会夺走一切
No, you gonna take away everything.
人们的家庭 他们的朋友
People's families, their friends.
我的朋友
My friends.
他们在那个星球上有自己的生活
They have lives on that planet.
每个人都是如此
Everyone does.
除了我们
Except for us.
我几乎认不出你 巴兹
I hardly recognize you, Buzz.
所有这些新的想法...
All these new ideas...
你知道吗？
You know what?
我们把这些也删掉吧
We'll go ahead and erase those too.
-哇哦 -我给你买了5分钟
-Whoa. -I bought you five minutes.
为什么？
Why?
我喜欢这个新的你
I like this new you.
我们必须摧毁这艘船
We have to destroy this ship.
你能把我带到舰桥吗？
Can you get me to the bridge?
当然可以 跟着我
Certainly. Follow me.
祖格
Zurg.
惊喜派对行动 我们开始吧
Operation Surprise Party, here we go.
Zap, zap!
我们需要保护我们的逃生船
We need to protect our escape ship.
所以 不要让任何机器人从那扇门进来
So, don't let any robots come through that door.
别担心 我们会把它封住的
Don't worry, we'll seal it off.
你去找巴兹
You go find Buzz.
我会追踪他狗牌上的芯片
I'll track the chip in his dog tags.
喵喵
Meow meow.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我收到两个巴斯的信号 这不可能是正确的
I'm getting two Buzz signals. That's can't be right.
我将进行三角定位  这将使我们足够接近 来吧
I'll triangulate.  That will get us close enough. Come on.
一条回去的捷径
A shortcut back.
这是很好的
This is pretty neat.
我们得走了
We have to go.
是的 好的
Yep, all right.
哦 太好了
Oh, great.
我不知道这些控制
I don't know any of these controls.
等等 I. V. A. N. ？
Wait. I.V.A.N.?
是的 上尉？
Yes, Captain?
孩子 我很高兴见到你
Boy, am I glad to see you.
两分钟后启动自毁程序
Initiate self-destruct sequence  in two minutes.
你说对了 自毁倒计时开始
You got it. Self-destruct countdown initiated.
巴斯 你不想要这些很酷的技术吗？
Buzz, you don't want  any of this cool technology?
只有你 夥计 来吧
Only you, buddy, come on.
-叛徒！-不
-Traitor! -No.
够了！
Enough!
只要告诉我水晶在哪里
Just tell me where the crystal is.
好吧 我们得保护我们的逃生船
Okay, we've gotta protect our escape ship.
那么 我们如何关闭这扇门呢？
So, how do we close this door?
我不知道
I don't know.
你说 "别担心 我们会把它封住的 "
What? You said, "don't worry we'll seal it off."
对 所以别担心 我们会的
Right, so don't worry. We will.
在这里 我们走了
Here we go.
看 看到了吗？
Look, see?
什么？
What?
喵喵喵
Meow meow.
现在信号更紧了
The signal is tighter now.
他必须在这边直走
He has to be straight this way.
那是一个很大的空间
That's a lot of space.
保持在一起 保持在一起
Keep it together. Keep it together.
不！
No!
我不明白  信号显示巴兹在50米外
I don't understand.  The signal says Buzz is 50 meters away.
他在那边
He's over there.
你以为我们不一样吗 巴斯？
You think we're not the same, Buzz?
你已经是我了 只是你还不知道
You're already me, you just don't know it yet.
我永远不会成为你！
I'm never gonna be you!
如果你不成为我 你就不会成为任何人
If you're not gonna be me  you're not gonna be anyone.
人工重力解除
Artificial gravity disengaged.
爆炸
Blast.
不 不
No, no.
-嘿 你在做什么？-造一个炸弹
-Hey, what are you doing? -Building a bomb.
不错 你需要笔吗？
Nice, do you need a pen?
不 给你
No. Here.
哦 谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
薄荷糖
Peppermint.
把包装纸给我
Give me the wrapper.
那么 你就可以用这些东西造一个炸弹了？
So, you can just build a bomb  out of that stuff?
我用得少  现在把口香糖给我
I worked with less.  Now give me the gum.
等等 我还没说完 还有很多味道
Wait, I'm not done,  there's still a lot of flavor left.
来吧！
Come on!
在那里 当他们踩到它的时候 它就会炸开
There. When they step on it  it will blow up.
如果他们不踩呢？
What if they don't step on it?
我是说 我不会踩上去的 你会吗？
I mean, I wouldn't step on that,  would you?
那我们就得往上面扔重物
Then we need to drop something heavy on it.
-只是要... -不！
-Just gonna... -No!
巴兹？
Buzz?
巴斯？ 巴斯！
Buzz!
阿丽莎？
Alisha?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
不 我一个人做不到 我需要帮助
No. I can't do it alone. I need help.
我不是我奶奶
I'm not my grandma.
伊兹 我不需要你的奶奶 我需要你
Izzy, I don't need your grandma,  I need you.
索克斯 我们怎么去那里？
Sox, how do we get over there?
通过气闸
Through the airlock.
通过那里？
Through there?
外面什么都没有
There's nothing out there.
正是如此 没有东西挡住你的路
Exactly. Nothing in your way.
你就直接过去吧
You just go straight across.
不！
No!
让我把话说清楚 当这东西落在你的炸弹上时
Let me get this straight,  when this falls on your bomb
-它一定会爆炸的 -是的
-it will definitely explode. -Yes.
-那就能封住门？-是的
-And that will seal the door? -Yes.
但是我们最好快点
But we better hurry.
我正在抓紧时间
I am hurrying.
你为什么不快点呢？
Why don't you hurry?
来吧
Come on.
好的
Okay.
来吧 Izzy
Come on, Izzy.
你得到这个
You got this.
哦 夥计
Oh, man.
哦 不
Oh, no.
只要不往下看 也不往上看  这都是空间
Just don't look down, or up.  It's all space.
它无处不在 在你周围
It's everywhere. All around you.
我很抱歉 我可能没有帮助
I'm sorry, I'm probably not helping.
只管直走
Just go straight.
一旦你推开了 你就会走到那个方向
Once you push off  that the direction you'll go.
但如果我错过了呢？
But what if I miss?
不要错过
Don't miss.
什么？哦 不
What? Oh, no.
不 不！
No, no!
哇！
Whoa!
索克斯！
Sox!
谢谢你 Izzy
Thank you, Izzy.
没有办法进去
There is no way in.
也许我可以帮忙
Perhaps I could help.
你不能为我躲起来 巴兹
You can't hide for me, Buzz.
这就像躲避自己
It's like hiding from yourself.
我总会找到你的
I'll always find you.
手动超控启动
Manual override activated.
-巴兹！-现在！
-Buzz! -Now!
来吧 让我们离开这里！
Come on, let's get outta here!
我们必须炸毁这艘船
We have to blow up the ship.
没有时间了 我们不可能成功的
There's no time. We'll never make it.
哦 是的 我们会的
Oh, yes, we will.
自毁程序在10分钟内完成...
Self-destruct sequence complete in ten...
-... 九 八... -I.V.A.N. ？I.V.A.N.!
-...nine, eight... -I.V.A.N.? I.V.A.N.!
Zurg.
达比 我们必须投降
Darby, we have to surrender.
不 我不会放弃的
No! I am not giving up.
是的 我也是 坚持住
Yep, neither am I. Hold on.
-... 五 四... -我们走吧
-...five, four... -Let's go.
-... ...三 二...  -每个人都上车
-...three, two...  -Everyone, get in.
...一
...one.
巴斯光年任务记录
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
我们已经摧毁了扎克的飞船和扎克本人
We've destroyed the Zurg's ship and Zurg himself.
现在我只需要追上犰狳号 以便...
Now I just have to catch up  to the Armadillo in order to--
要去哪里？
Going somewhere?
警告 引擎损坏是灾难性的
Warning, engine damage is catastrophic.
巴斯光年任务记录 我现在拥有了水晶
Buzz Lightyear mission log. I now have the crystal in my possession,
最后终于可以完成任务了
and can finally, at long last  finish the mission.
我要回去再做一次事 巴斯
I'm gonna go back and matter again, Buzz.
你呢？
And you?
你会像你从来没有来过一样
You will be like you have never here.
准备好去死吧
Prepare to die.
今天不行 祖格
Not today, Zurg.
我们已经进入了这个星球的引力范围
We've entered  the planet's gravitational pull.
我们会坠毁吗？
Are we gonna crash?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
巴兹！
Buzz!
我做不到
I can't do it.
巴斯 没关系的
Buzz, it's okay.
我们可以
We can.
你能保持船的稳定吗？
Can you keep the ship steady?
是的 我想可以
Yeah. I think so.
好的 索克斯 把应急电池与飞行控制的电源熔合
Okay, Sox, fuse the emergency battery the power of flight controls.
明白了
Got it.
我需要一个副驾驶
I'll need a co-pilot.
好的 但我只在模拟器上做过这个
Okay, but I've only done this  in the simulator.
好了 马上就要动真格的了
Well, it's about to get real.
记住 向后拉动操纵杆--
Remember, pull back on the yoke--
-容易 -是的 对不起 从现在开始 漂亮而轻松
-Easy. -Yep. Sorry. Nice and easy from now on.
没用的！
It's not working!
我们进去的速度太快了
We're going in too fast.
-I. V. A. N. -是的 船长？
-I.V.A.N. -Yes, Captain?
-我们走得太快了 -恭喜你！
-We're going too fast. -Congratulations!
我们不需要纸屑 我们需要刹车！
We don't need confetti, we need brakes!
哦 我知道！
Oh, I know!
-空气刹车！-在地板上
-The air brake! -On the floor.
达比！
Darby!
-它被卡住了 -什么？
-It's stuck. -What?
盖子 它被卡住了
The cover, it's stuck.
我需要一把螺丝刀 或者一把剪子
I need a screwdriver, or a hair clipper
某种小的楔子
Some sort of a small wedge.
我已经拿到了笔！
I've got the pen!
-巴兹！- 大家都还好吗？
-Buzz! - Is everyone okay?
-是的  -我想是的
-Yeah. -I think so.
警察来了！大家快跑！
The cops! Everybody, run!
等等 这只是救援队
Wait. It's just the rescue team.
对 好的
Right. Okay.
你看起来是个正直的公民 是什么导致了你被监禁？
You seem like a decent citizen. What led to your incarceration?
我偷了一艘船
I stole a ship.
我们中谁没有在... ...相对绝望的时候偷过一艘船？
Who among us hasn't stolen a ship  in a moment of...
相对绝望的时候？
relative desperation?
我是一个有资源的人 我的武器是聪明才智
I'm a man of resources. My weapon is ingenuity.
我可以做任何事情！
I can do anything!
你能不在我耳边大喊吗？
Can you not shout in my ear?
是的 对不起
Yep, sorry.
你还好吗？
You're okay?
su.b .T
我在太空中
I was in space.
你奶奶会很骄傲的
Your grandma would be proud.
她也会为你感到骄傲
She'd be proud of you too.
她总是这样
She always was.
等等 你的水晶在哪里？
Wait. Where is your crystal?
它已经消失了
It's gone.
但你的任务...
But your mission...
你想回家
You wanted to go home.
你知道吗 这么久以来第一次
You know, for the first time  in a long time
我觉得我回家了
I feel like I am home.
祖格
Zurg.
小心！
Look out!
哇？
Whoa?
马上停下来！
Stop right now!
光年
Lightyear.
你潜逃了星际司令部的财产 偷了实验性飞船
You absconded with Star Command property, stolen experimental spacecraft
并违抗指挥官的直接命令
and defied a direct order  from your commander.
我得把你扔进禁闭室
I gotta throw you into stockade.
但我对你有别的计划
But I have other plans for you.
我们想让你建立一个新版本的太空游侠团
We want you to start a new version  of the Space Ranger Corps.
宇宙保护部
Universe Protection Division.
你将再次成为一名太空游侠 巴兹
You're gonna be  a Space Ranger again, Buzz.
你可以从扎普巡逻队的精英中亲自挑选你的团队
You can hand-select your team  from the very best of the Zap Patrol
并按照你的喜好训练他们
and train them to your liking.
啪啪啪！啪啪啪！
Zap, zap!
好吧 你真好 先生
Well, that's very kind of you, sir.
但恐怕我不得不拒绝
But I'm afraid  I'm going to have to decline.
我已经有了我的团队
I already have my team.
这些新的套装是惊人的 臂部爆破器 火箭翼
These new suits are amazing. Arm blaster, rocket wings.
不过它可以用一支笔
It could use a pen though.
我不敢相信我被允许携带这个  我希望我有两个
I can't believe I'm allowed to carry this.  I wish I had two of them.
你有一个干净的记录  而且你是自由的和武装的
You got a clean record. and you're free and armed.
你怎么还在抱怨？
How are you still complaining?
我是因为行为良好而被释放的 不是因为态度好
I got off for good behavior,  not good attitude.
你知道 我从不穿裤子
You know, I never wear pants,
但突然不穿裤子的感觉很奇怪
but suddenly it feels weird  to not be wearing pants.
不穿裤子看起来很奇怪吗？
Does it look weird without pants?
不 你看起来很好
No, you look good.
我希望我可以把它拉下来
I wish I could pull that off.
看 奶奶 我是一名太空游侠
Look, Grandma, I'm a Space Ranger.
就像你一样
Just like you.
好了 队员们 我们在第四区的伽马象限发现了一个信号
All right, team, we've picked up a signal  in the Gamma Quadrant of Sector 4.
我们不知道它是什么 但我们不会等待它来入侵我们的家园
We don't know what it is, but we're not  gonna wait for it to invade our home.
收到 指挥官 你可以指望我们
Copy, Commander. You can count on us.
巴斯光年任务日志 星际日期4071年
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date 4071.
作为宇宙精英保护小组的成员
As members  of the Elite Universe Protection Unit
作为太空游骑兵部队的成员
of the Space Ranger Corps,
我们的任务是保护银河系不受任何银河联盟的死敌入侵
we've been charged to protect the galaxy  from the threat of invasion
来自银河联盟的任何死敌
from any sworn enemies  of The Galaxy Alliance.
好了 各位 请确保你们都系好了安全带
Okay, everyone, make sure  you're securely fastened.
-我们都准备好了吗？弹药？-检查
-Do we have everything? Munitions? -Check.
-营养品呢？-我带了三文治
-Sustenance? -I brought sandwiches.
你的肚子会好吗？
And your tummy will be okay?
-都准备好了 -好的
-All set. -All right.
我是不是忘了什么？
Am I forgetting anything?
我想我们已经准备好了
I think we're ready.
你好 我是你的内部声控导航员
Hello, I am your internal voice-activated navigator.
很高兴你能回来 I. V. A. N.
Good to have you back, I.V.A.N.
光年船长 准备发射
Captain Lightyear, ready for launch.
-索克斯？-喵？
-Sox? -Meow?
喵？ I.V.A.N. 启动超级发射
I.V.A.N., initiate hyper-launch.
当然可以
Certainly.
好了 太空游侠 我们来了
All right, Space Rangers. Here we go.
到无穷大
To infinity
和超越
and beyond.
请继续关注01:35:50和01:43:37的两段片尾字幕场景 欢呼吧！sub.T
Keep tuned for TWO post credit scenes  at 01:35:50 and 01:43:37. Cheers. sub.T
转载：sub.Trader subscene.com
Transcript by sub.Trader subscene.com
激光盾牌
Laser shield.
现在 如果你更喜欢一条风景优美的路线
Now, should you prefer  a more scenic route
你会想往南走 经过溴化石沼泽
you'll want to head south past the bromite swamps,
一个令人歎为观止的景象 或者说我是这么听说的
a breathtaking sight, or so I am told.
但如果你赶时间 这将是你最直接的路线
But if you are in a hurry, this would be your most direct route.
有问题吗？
Any questions?
你好？
Hello?